DEVAN POTTER-BONAR

107-1300 Richmond Road Ottawa, Ontario K2B 8L2

Phone: (613) 864-4869 | Email: devan.potter.bonar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/devanpotterbonar | Github: github.com/Adpbonar

Portfolio: www.devanpotterbonar.com

SUMMARY

Endowed with a life-long dedication to learning, Devan is a Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Political Science and Communication. His experience in front line sales and marketing helps him excel at combining creativity and problem solving, to develop user-friendly applications that meet his clients needs. Known by his coworkers for wit, loyalty and attention to detail no matter the project; He is an asset to organizations that require team cohesion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: English (fluent), French (functional), Robust writing, editing and research skills

Applications: Microsoft Office, Gimp, Audacity, InVision Studio, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Zoom

Programing Languages & Frameworks: Ruby/Rails, Javascript, React, JQuery, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap and Foundation

PROJECTS

Chesster | github.com/Toronto-s-Optimistic-Agile-Developers/Chesster | toad-chesster.herokuapp.com

- An online chess game where users can play against one another.
- Developed as part of an Agile team working together to complete various aspects of gameplay.
- <u>Languages used</u>: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

devanpotterbonar.com | github.com/Adpbonar/dev-s-portfolio | www.devanpotterbonar.com

- A portfolio and blog app that showcases, my experience and articles related to my programming journey.
- Developed, by me, to facilitate my career change.
- <u>Languages used</u>: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

NoteApp | github.com/Adpbonar/todo | notes-app-devanpotterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A note app was built in React offered. It uses an API to manage and render notes and tags.
- Developed as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp.
- Languages used: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, React

The TO-DO List | github.com/Adpbonar/todo | todolist-devanpotterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A single page todo-mvc application that features a fluid user interface. By using JavaScript users can rapidly add dynamic content.
- Developed as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp.
- <u>Languages used</u>: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

Devan Potter-Bonar - 2 -

Flixster | github.com/Adpbonar/Flixter Project | flixter-devan-potterbonar.herokuapp.com

- A two-sided, video-streaming marketplace platform that features credit card payment capabilities. It also includes user role management, complex user interfaces, and advanced database relationships.
- Developed the app as part of the University of Toronto Coding Bootcamp.
- <u>Languages used</u>: Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

Director, Administration & Operations

2015 - Present

Bonar Institute for Purposeful Leadership

Ottawa, Ontario

As Director, Administration & Operations, wide-ranging duties including:

- Implementing a consistent brand design across platforms
- Creating marketing materials in print, online and on our app
- Developing methods to facilitate client interaction and ease the collection of information to complete mandates
- Adapting and entering content

Key Accomplishments:

- Coding in html5, selecting photos and designing graphics to showcase our brand experience within our app
- Evolving the brand to reflect app design flourishes
- Liaising with representatives of the app design company to articulate our vision and iron out issues as they arise
- Producing graphics and other promotional materials for the Bonar Institute websites (both English and French)
- Creating modals and customizing navigation of the site
- Ongoing upkeep

Receiver 2016 – Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Receiver, wide-ranging duties including:

- Supporting the management team by ordering products and managing staff in their absence
- Creating positive strong relationships with vendors and taking the lead on inventory and backroom management
- Driving sales by taking on customer service and cashier management roles, as required

Cashier Supervisor 2012 – Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Cashier Supervisor, at two locations, I was often the first management figure to interact with customers and ensure positive shopping experiences by:

- Supervising cashiers resolving issues as they arose
- Ensuring exemplary customer experience
- Troubleshooting technical difficulties
- Promoting customer loyalty, and addressing staffing and maintenance issues as they arose
- Preparing the daily store deposits

Cashier 2012 - Present

Shopper Drug Mart Ottawa, Ontario

As Cashier Supervisor, duties including:

- Supervising cashiers resolving issues as they arose, at multiple locations
- Ensuring exemplary customer experience
- Troubleshooting technical difficulties
- Promoting customer loyalty, and addressing staffing and maintenance issues as they arose
- Preparing the daily store deposits

Devan Potter-Bonar - 3 -

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

A 24-week intensive online program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

During this course, students built projects in using the Rails framework and React to learn how to code and hone our skills with algorithms. The culmination: An agile team project to enhance our skills and prepare us to work in this exciting field.

Coursework towards a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science, minor in Communication Studies: Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario